Mhm.
So once again
umbrella
in fact,
Allah says in sort of Gujarat
that if two groups of believers are fighting each other,
then
I'll describe them as A and B. Are fighting
A and B are fighting
then
see
should make peace
for us lee who
but you know how much
peace between them is
too long?
I'll even remove seeds. So it's all in one line if nbr fighting C should make peace.
So if two groups of believers fight
the rest of you,
which is C should make peace between them first different
now for
if
A
fights be again
in other words, you made peace, you brought everybody together.
You are the peace negotiators.
You brought them together.
He said come on guys, stop fighting, shake hands, hug each other
done, it's ended, it's finished.
You left the room and a started fighting again
against B.
He says
umbrella
then be
and C should fight
who?
Hey,
that's the formula right now. Thus far, I'm trying to make it as clear as possible.
In the beginning. Was C involved in the fight? Were you involved in the fight?
No, you were involved in making the peace.
You called the meeting, You called the two parties. Everybody came to an agreement.
We're not going to fight any more than one of
those parties broke the agreement and started fighting again.
Now they are not just the enemy of be there also
your enemy because they broke the agreement.
Your responsibility is not to fight the one who broke the
agreement that comes with the responsibility of being a community.
So now you must fight together against a
umbrella until it comes back to Allah's command meaning until they until you
go back to in a state of peace again meaning a says okay,
okay, okay
fine
peace
now.
If it does if a stops fighting
for in fact if they come back
come back to the negotiations table, they're no longer fighting again
for
sadly then she should make
peace
between who
and be
with justice
and make sure
to not to
not to be unfair.
It's interesting language
how many times in this discussion did the words make peace come up?
How many times did make peace come up
twice? Once in the beginning she should make peace
then when did it come up again?
So you should make peace
again.
But the second time that it came up
the second time that it came up, although I didn't just say make peace between them,
he said make peace between them with justice.
The first time he didn't say make peace with justice.
He only said that the second time.
Which is peculiar.
If you are the peace negotiator
then you are expected to be just every time.
I only mentioned justice once and not the other time.
You understand that the curiosity here
the change in language here.
Okay.
You see the rest of us the community, everybody, we are naturally neutral.
We're naturally neutral.
So when two of us are fighting,
everybody else gets involved and we solve the fight and who do we who do we side with
nobody. We side with peace because we're neutral.
Now you invited two of your friends to your house.
They were fighting each other. You invited them to your house.
They shook hands on it. In your observation.
You were the ones who brokered the peace agreement.
They leave the house and one of them punches the other one in your driveway.
Now you come out, you watch the whole thing happen.
Who will you fight against
the guy who threw the punch?
Now two of you are fighting against the one
and then he says okay okay okay fine fine.
Let's talk again.
Now you come back in the living room
when you come back in the living room the second time
something has changed
the first time around be was angry with a a was angry with be
the second time you came back in the living room.
Who's angry?
Is is the one who did the crime.
So who else is angry bees angry obviously who else is angry?
The question is why is he angry?
Why is he angry? First of all see says I bordered this peace agreement.
I brought you to my house,
you agreed with me and then you disrespect me by violating my agreement.
Second of all the command of Allah is that if you violate my agreement,
not only will be fight you
see I will fight you to and if you were
just fighting weren't you angry when you were fighting.
So now you have a tendency because you're still the judge, you're still the judge.
There's a tendency that you will now side with B
more than you will with
A. Because you were just fighting alongside be against A.
I know there's a lot of abc is here.
What am I am I making sense here?
Okay,
so the second time around you're supposed to be the peace negotiator again.
But there's a tendency that you have a bias now against A
So you have to be told this time when you make peace,
make sure you do it with
justice because there is a danger
that you will be unfair
for
belatedly were accessible.
Make sure you do it with justice
and make sure that you are fair. Now
this makes sure not to be unfair and justice. This sounds like the same thing.
It sounds like the same thing.
Being being just and not being unfair is the same thing to us.
Why? Say it twice over like this.
I need you to understand the difference between two kinds of words used for justice.
There's adam
which is justice
and there's this
which is
the lack of injustice.
It's literally what that means is the lack of injustice.
Okay.
But there's another difference between these two words.
Adele is open,
public,
transparent
and kissed is
public
or private.
That's a big difference between I didn't list
the court is called.
Why because it's open,
it's one of the reasons it's called our data.
Okay.
No
the first time around you were told to
make peace between them now imagine who's fighting.
By the way,
Muslims are fighting each other in the Iowa Muslims are
fighting each other and by the way they're not even Muslims
you have to assume that everybody is not just muslim their movement.
You don't get to call someone a
not in this idea. Don't even just get to call the muslim.
You have to call them moment in other words,
you don't even get to judge their faith because
there's a tendency that when Muslims are fighting,
they call each other names.
Right? So love protected that tendency said no.
Even if you have a fight there's still a movement and you're still a movement.
Watch it.
You see Alice says these things because these are real problems and we violate them.
And if we paid attention to Corrine would realize what we're doing.
But anyway, come back to the problem to Muslims are fighting each other.
Is that an embarrassment when to Muslims are fighting each other.
Absolutely.
So when you are negotiating the peace between them.
Should it happen openly in front of everyone or privately
it should happen privately called him into your house into the living room,
into the conference room at the mustard or something
and you go and you privately figure things out.
Listen this is what you did. This is what you did.
I don't want to bring your issues up in front of the entire community.
I want this to be private so that we quietly
deal with this problem and we move on with life.
Okay now it was done quietly but a troublemaker.
A he comes out of the meeting and even though
he agreed inside the meeting that everything is okay,
he came out of the meeting and said you don't know what happened inside there man.
It was private. They're all against me. I'm the victim here.
I'm going to start fighting again.
And he took advantage of the fact that the meeting was private.
You see if the meeting was public,
what would happen?
He cannot say,
well you don't know what happened in there because everybody
knows what happened in there because it's on Youtube.
You understand it's it's public
but the fact that it's private was important. He took advantage of it.
So the next time you bring him after the fighting is over and he says,
okay fine let's negotiate again no longer.
Can you negotiate privately this time?
Even though it's super embarrassing in order to prevent future
problems this time when you bring them back to court,
this has to be what
open because he can't be trusted anymore.
So it has to be open. Also you can't be trusted anymore because you're angry.
So it has to be open.
This is why
was used
make peace between them using open public transparent justice.
This is going to be important
by the way
in the justice system when you have a trial that is private
closed doors,
no cameras, no journalists,
no recordings, anything. Do people trust those trials or no,
no.
Why do you have to hide it?
If you hide it there must be something wrong,
there must be some kind of injustice going on.
So align the IA describes when people want to solve their problems privately,
give them that chance,
but if they violate and they're hurting others and they're doing
crime then you have to bring it out in the open.
This is an important principle for the muslim community. Why?
Because we have people in our community sometimes who do terrible things
who are damaging community
but we say no, no, no protect your brother, keep it private
and they get away with it once and twice and three times and
four times and we still try to keep it private the first time.
Keep it private every other time. What?
Open up and open to the public. It has to be in public.
This is the formula is teaching us from solving community problems
but then I want to show you this oxygen
okay do justice publicly. Why say oxy
oxy to actually means and be fair public or
private and make sure you try not to be unfair. In other words
l kissed is actually more about the individual and ladle is more about the,
the overall,
the communal,
so lie saying at the individual level, you all should be fair to begin with.
Fighting would not have happened if one of you didn't have a twisted moral compass.
If one of you did not have a bad sense of justice,
none of this conflict would have happened.
So overall,
you should emphasize the need for personal responsibility in the community.
Everybody has to stand up for their own standards of justice.
It's also important that Allah did not say in Allah
Allah loves those who show justice publicly.
Actually, Allah loves those who are just publicly and
privately. That's why Mark sitting at the end.
Now let's talk about our sense of justice,
my personal sense of justice, Your personal sense of justice.
Your parents are sometimes paying for your college and university fees.
They're paying for them.
You're getting the education and your parents are paying for them.
Now you're going to class late,
you're not doing your assignments.
You don't care about your exams,
you don't care about attendance, don't care about anything.
Nobody finds out and finds out. Your mother doesn't know you're missing classes.
You're father doesn't know
you're watching movies
when your mother calls you and you're at a restaurant with your friends
in the middle of your supposed to be in class,
but your restaurant at a restaurant and she calls you
and you pick up the phone mom.
I can't talk right now.
I'm in the library
not realizing that your mother is sitting at the next table.
You have to hold yourself to a higher standard of justice.
The riot of the Koran are not just about recitation in the mustard and
that's important.
The heart of the Koran is about our, about how you live your life,
how you spend your money,
how how how diligent and how honest you are in your workplace.
Are you earning your money or are you just
sitting there at the desk collecting a paycheck?
Are you actually doing what you're supposed to do? Do you have the work ethic?
You know,
did you just get your job because you have some
connections and then you're just sitting on vacation all day,
you know, surfing the web.
I even tell people don't listen to Islamic lectures when you're at work,
you're not there to listen to Islamic lectures, you're there to do work.
No brother, I watch your videos all the time at my job.
I was like please don't watch my videos
at your job.
Don't drag me into your problems bro,
Just do your job.
No, but it's Islam.
Yes it is.
You wanna watch Islamic lectures, watch them at home. Work is for work to stop.
Little love starved woman said I shouldn't learn Islam.
Yes. When you're being paid to do work, you shouldn't be learning Islam.
You should be doing work because that's what you're being paid to do
now unless your boss comes to you and says listen, I know there's no work right now,
we're in between contracts a little bit low season in the middle,
so relax if you want to, you know, you can tell your boss,
hey boss until there's some work you mind if I listen
to a lecture or two and your boss says no problem,
okay,
no problem. You're not because you didn't cheat your boss, you're not hiding it.
You didn't, you know all tab every time he walks by
you. So it's,
it's clear, it's open,
have a sense of justice at your work and your school,
you know,
some of the, some of the younger kids here, they just lie man, they just lie.
Did you do your homework? Yes,
Did you pray? Yes.
You just say did you?
And they just say yes before you even finish did yes, I did, I did it.
What we'll do, I said homework,
what did you do? Well do with homework,
homework to do?
You know,
and you can tell when kids are lying
because they're really strong in their answer
I did, I did, I really did. That means you didn't
the,
you don't have to go out of your way like that
unless there's a problem
like your kid comes in and says I didn't punch anyone, okay
that
you should know what just happened.
So
I want to give you an example of
beautiful word usage and
is just one example
and Shaolin will conclude this section,
we're making good progress I think
has used one of the words in Arabic for purification.
So the idea is translated in general english translation.
So Allah may cleanse those who believe
so let me cleanse those or purify those who believe in,
Let me give you a little bit of context to the idea.
So you can appreciate the word for cleansing here, you could use
like you heard
before, I'm sure right,
you can use a number of words for cleansing but also uses specifically at
now,
this is about the battle of
and Muslims suffered some great losses in the battle of
were murdered
and the prophecy salam was knocked unconscious and the
Muslims had to retreat up the mountain if that
when you were climbing up the hill and weren't turning back to even look at anybody,
this is the, this is the horrible scenario of
and Allah says that he put us through this
scenario so that he could cleanse those who believe
one of the purposes of the difficulty of good was sala,
could cleanse those who believe.
Now interestingly the word that's used for cleansing
that you will not see in translation.
Adam Hayes is actually used when you purify gold
when you purify gold. Now gold has impurities
so you have to melt it,
you cannot just use a sponge
and purify gold, you have to melt it
and turn it into liquid.
And the impurities that are deep inside the metal come
out to the top and you know turn into froth
and and wither away. Then you get pure gold. You understand
now this is different from cleaning dishes or cleaning clothes because
cleaning dishes and cleaning clothes is obviously a lot easier than cleaning
gold purifying gold.
You understand because you have a lot of intense
heat that's involved interestingly enough by saying this,
Elias saying believers cannot be cleaned unless they are put to the flames,
right?
If you want to cleanse the believing community,
they have to be put to the flames and the flames in this case are the flames of war.
So you had to be put under intense temperatures in order for you to be cleansed.
Also in the by using this word,
it is as though Allah is saying that what
is being cleansed of impurities are being removed.
Remember when I told you in the story of
and medina that in difficult times hypocrites expose themselves.
But if you and I
have a difficult time.
Yes, I did.
The believers exposed the the hypocrites exposed themselves in the hood.
Absolutely, they did. In other words now lies calling the hypocrites impurities
just indirectly through the same imagery allies saying that the hypocrites are
and impurity and the only way this and also he's saying
that this impurity is deeply embedded inside the muslim community.
And the only way to get it out is to
really put the muslim community enters a very difficult,
intense temperature,
difficult circumstance and they will just rise to the top and disappear
just in one word.
But the other awesome thing here is not only by
using this word did a law called the hypocrites filth,
he also called the Sahaba Gold.
Hmm
If you did so much, just by using the right word for cleansing, the believer's.
Okay, So let's move along.
Oh this is gonna be fun.
And I have four sections here. Oh I have a lot more sections.
I'll pretend I have three sections here.
This is section one, this is two, this is three.
Don't be offended
for what I'm about to do with you.
Okay,
bear with me
this side of the class.
This over here.
People who failed,
Don't be offended
this side of the class.
People who passed
this side of the class,
My teacher's assistants.
They're not teachers, are my assistants.
So these two sides are students,
this one in the middle, are my
assistance
or let me even take you one better. This side failed.
These are my assistants.
These guys have an exam tomorrow.
We'll see what happens
now.
You guys did what
you failed. So I'm yelling at you. Hey, how could you fail? I prepared you so much.
I gave you so much review. I gave you so many answers.
I even gave you the answer key during the test,
How could you fail
while I'm talking to you. Can they hear me
okay?
And I turned to you and say,
can you make sure they do their homework?
Why am I telling you that?
Because your teacher's assistant, your job is to assist me in teaching them.
Can you make sure they do their homework?
Can you make sure they don't fail the next test?
And I know it's not your fault.
These people are losers.
Then I turned to you.
We'll see what happens tomorrow.
Because there are three sections.
One of me as a teacher, I'm actually having three conversations, aren't I?
One with you, One with you, One with you.
But even though I'm having three conversations, can all of you hear me?
Yes.
And is it having an effect on each group?
Even if I'm not talking to you? Is it still affecting you?
As I'm yelling at them? What's happening to this group?
They're terrified.
Oh my God! He's gonna yell at us tomorrow
after we fail.
This group is nervous.
Did they fail? Because we didn't do our job.
You understand?
So there's a lot of dynamics happening in the classroom.
This is the scenario of teaching
in teaching the teachers, having conversations with multiple parties.
I want you to understand that the Koran Allah is teaching us,
which means there are multiple parties being addressed at the same time.
And what's amazing in the Koran is sometimes multiple parties are being addressed
simultaneously in one eye
in one island.
Let's go through this a little bit.
A lot of religion says
this time I'm gonna change the groups
This time there are two groups
And this is Group one
This is Group two.
Don't be offended.
This is Denise Ryan
and these are the Muslims,
Denise Ryan.
What's up?
No listen
I gave you shade with clouds.
Well
silva and we sent onto you manna and Salwa
eat and drink from the things that we provided you. That's what I said to you.
Eat and drink.
I gave you clouds. I gave you manna. I gave you Sandra. I said eat and drink.
Get it
muna
moon. They didn't commit a crime against me.
They only committed crimes against themselves.
Half of the Iowa alot is talking to who
when it's slightly
the other half of the Iowa who's a lot talking to
Muslims. How do I know because half the Iowa's uu uu then is they they they they
if the whole, I was about beneath
you will find you the entire time.
Allah is talking to
but who's listening. He knows who's in the room. Who else is listening.
When Allah talks to
the Muslims there listening and Allah is yelling at
and he's telling them. I give you so many chances.
I did so many wonderful things for you.
What is wrong and you know what, I'm so angry with you.
I don't even want to talk to you anymore.
I'll tell you guys you guys are up next, I give them a chance. You're up next.
They didn't wrong me, They wronged themselves.
What am I trying to tell you if a low tolerance
to you and says they didn't commit a crime against us,
they committed a crime against themselves?
What is Allah telling the Muslims,
Allah is telling the Muslims you better not do the same thing
because I'm going to give you a bunch of stuff now
I'm gonna give you a lot of gifts now
and if you
those gifts
you better watch it.
You know what this does,
it changes my perspective on the study of history altogether.
Dr
does not talk about Ben Israel so I get to say ah
to know I hear about
and I got terrified because half the I was about
and the other half was about me and you and Allah is saying watch it,
you're next,
it's your turn now
let's see what happens.
Is it within the island,
you gotta look out for these shifts. This is called,
that's the technical term,
you can call it a transition meaning a lot goes from you to he
you today they to us
I two we he switches and those switches are you gotta keep up,
you gotta keep up, I'll give you another one, this is an awesome one.
This is a
this is this is a transition about time travel.
I don't know if I'm going to be able to do my job explaining this one to you.
But if you get it, you will really enjoy it.
I hope I'm clear in explaining this one to you.
The Ia begins with what will happen in jena
it begins not with Dona what with
and it doesn't begin with you. It begins with they
it begins with they so it's not you, it's someone else.
They will be eating fruits and they will
be enjoying themselves and they'll be smiling.
Big smiles on their faces
like they've had
mangosteen or something
and they're just smiling
because of what Allah has given them and he has
protected them from the punishment of the roaring flame.
They feel secure and protected and happy you are they
they now we're in the future.
So it's they and it's in the future which means it's two degrees of distance from you.
One sense of distance from you because it's not you,
it's someone else second because it's not now it's in the future.
So it's distant in terms of time and space,
it's far from you.
Then immediately
honey and
eat
and drink
carefree.
Not they will eat and they will drink carefree. He says eat and drink carefree.
When do you say eat and drink?
Do you say that to someone who's there or someone who's not there.
Someone who's there,
but Allah is talking to you and me and he wasn't talking about me,
he was talking about someone else whose agenda and all of
a sudden he says to me eat and drink carefree.
Why?
Because he forced me in this Ia he forced me to imagine
myself in Jenna and Ally is telling me to eat and drink carefree
in a split second,
the Iaea began and I thought those people in general, they're so far from me,
I wish I could be from them
halfway through the eye and
he doesn't even
and it will be said to them. No time for that. No, no, you you eat and drink.
You eat and drink carefree Now. I am imagining myself in june 9 11 telling me to eat and
drink carefree.
Don't check for the halal label or nothing.
I just need
now. Am I imagining myself in the present or in the future?
You got to keep up with the times here.
I'm imagining myself in the future.
What does Allah say to me in the future? He says to me eat and drink carefree
balloon eat and drink carefree because of the wonderful things you used to do.
So let me mention in the future about what I used to do in the
past, which is technically the
present,
isn't it?
Because if Allah is saying in the future, you did a great job in the past,
the past must mean
right now. So I just traveled all throughout time and space in one area.
I traveled through it
and by the time the I was done, I realized something
Allah wants me to visualize myself in jena.
And as I am listening as I'm eating the fruits of gender. I am being told.
This is what you this is because of what you did when
right now.
If you understand the IA you put yourself to work when?
Right now
now what is the gift of a line in the ira,
the gift of liars. You get to eat
and you also get to what
drink and it's also carefree.
But that's not the real gift.
The real gift of the idea is you will be talking directly with Allah
a lot will be telling you you did a great job.
You know when your teacher
walks over to your desk and says
good job
for the teacher. It's nothing
for the students. It's everything.
Just one little compliment.
You don't even know what one little compliment can do
one little thing.
You know, we think we shouldn't praise people.
Some people have this twisted understanding of the religion.
You shouldn't praise people to stop,
only prays a lot.
God, you're so psychotic.
Why can't you be normal?
It's okay to praise people. Don't go crazy and crazy people like you're so amazing.
Like don't do that. But you can say nice job. I like what you did.
That's that's amazing. That was really good.
I really appreciate your help etcetera. You should praise people and thank people,
you should do it. It's a part of what we do. You're supposed to do that.
So now, you know, I'll tell you a story. I myself
I did not see myself going into the teaching profession at all.
I was into technology profession. I was doing okay.
And one time I did the, you know, in a mushroom
group, it was four people and they asked me to give a presentation and I did.
And one brother that I really looked up to because
he was actually a mentor to me in technology.
He was a four point oh G. P. A graduate out of the Master's program at M. I. T.
Thanks.
Yeah.
And he I did my presentation for five minutes. He said, you know what?
You're a natural teacher, you shouldn't consider teaching.
I'm telling you.
One of the big reasons I turned to this profession was those few words.
There's just so we can write this.
You don't know what some words can do,
especially when words come from someone you admire.
You don't know what they can do for you.
You know,
so don't be cheap in giving compliments.
Don't be cheap in giving compliments, especially to your kids.
You know, especially the friends, especially to those who look up to you
if you see something good in them admire it,
accepted
encouraging,
you know,
eat a drink. You did a great job just to hear from a lot that I did a great job.
Mhm.
I don't know if I want to eat anything anymore.
You know.
Okay,
now let's go on the scary side of things.
This kind of switch can also be scary.
They said
Rahman took a son
who's there,
Who's they?
Questions.
They said Rahman took us. And now when you say they that's far away.
It's not you, it's it's far away.
But you know
there's a switch that is about to happen.
You have come forward with something hideous. You have said something monstrous.
Not they have said something monstrous, but
you have said something mantras. So why switch from they to you?
Let me explain this one to you.
So I have a class and in the class there are two students who cheated on the test.
Okay. Two students cheated on the test.
I know which ones because their answers are exactly the same.
In the same handwriting.
And they're sitting in the back together.
I walk into the class with my stack of tests. I put it on the table.
I do my dramatic introduction.
Some people think they can get away with cheating.
They think that I don't know what the same handwriting looks like.
They think they can sit in the back row and I am blind to their behavior.
They they they they they they they they they they they they they they they
now the guy in the back
he says he doesn't know what happened.
He said they
he's mildly nervous but not really realizing that I actually
know it's him and I'm not giving it up yet.
I'm not saying you over there. I'm just using what word
they because I'm keeping a distant,
he's he's a little scared but still hoping it's not me.
But then in the middle of the day I say
said,
should I,
can I talk to you for a minute?
Oh,
the world comes to an end.
Mhm.
You know,
it's a terrifying thing when your name gets called after the day it goes to a U U.
Two over here,
You two my office now.
Oh my God, it's terrifying.
I love it.
I love it. It's so much fun.
I love one of the great,
one of the reasons I stayed in the teaching
profession is the ability to psychologically torture students.
It is one of the most satisfying things you will do in your life.
I have to share something with you here. You know, when you, when I give an exam,
I like to walk around the student,
he's writing his exam, I just walk over
and I look and he puts his elbow up and I look and he puts
it more and put some more and puts it on and put it away,
put it, you know,
And then here's my favourite one. You look over the exam
and you take a deep breath and you make sure they hear it
ah
and just walk away with your head shaking.
Mhm.
It is amazing
what happens next.
Okay.
Everything.
Here's one of my favorite ones.
It's a student
acting that you know it's a recess. Kids are the guys are like
you know playing table tennis or something and I walk over
and I say
Hassan,
can I see you in my office?
Ah is everything okay? I'll start
um in charlotte.
Was he in the office?
Hudson comes into my office,
have a seat actually and make sure he has a seat.
Then I sit on the other side and I have some empty papers that I go through
actually. I think you might want to close the door.
You don't say it at first, you wait, you let him get a little more nervous then you say,
I think you probably should probably close the door.
He closes the door.
You're sitting there
um start start. Is everything okay?
Um Actually I thought I I wanted to let you know
I was speaking with your parents about this.
You're doing a fantastic job, I'm very proud of you.
Ah
Okay
now could you go and call Kareem for me?
The joys of teaching, they tell you,
you know,
but in the Koran allies teaching
and sometimes a lot talks to people who
don't realize that what they're doing is super serious
and they're taking it casually.
So he introduces the subject with they so
they still feel distant that this is warning,
this is a warning that is not about them.
Then immediately he drops a you so they get oh it's about me what
you know
so this is you know
they should deny what we gave them.
Go ahead, enjoy yourself. You'll find out soon enough
you will find out.
So it goes from there to you.
These switches in the Koran by the way these kinds
of switches when you do them in english class,
your teacher marks it all wrong
If you start your paragraph with I use I the whole time.
If you started would he use he the whole time?
If you start with we use we the whole time. Isn't that what you get?
Corrine has its own standard.
Its own standard.
If you try to compare it to any other standard you just won't get the book.
You just don't get it. You don't want get what he's saying.
Now I want to give you one last example
of this transition but a visual example of transition.
A visual example.
This one is you have to just imagine that there's a camera that comes with the ill
Bari
Bari.
He Allah is the one who makes things easy for you on the land.
He facilitates travel for you in the land and in the ocean.
Now when he says the land and the ocean,
what do you imagine basically you imagine the shore or a harbor or a beach.
Why? Because you want to see land and you want to see
ocean
until the time when you board onto ships.
Now when you're boarding onto ships,
you're obviously going from the harbor from the dock
and you're loading yourselves on to the ship.
So you're, the ship is still kind of connected to the land.
What serena be him? And then the ships start sailing away with them
with good wind. Now what do you imagine you imagine the harbor? It's a sunny day.
People have loaded onto the ship.
They sail away and the winds are nice and the winds
are getting caught and the ship is moving quickly sailing away.
It's a beautiful scene and they're catching extra speed because the winds are good.
Okay
and they're very happy with the winds.
What a beautiful scene, sunny skies, gleaming, you know, sunlight in the water,
beautiful breeze.
Everybody's happy. This is going to be the most amazing cruise ever.
This is the greatest vacation I've ever had
out of a sudden all of a sudden a tornado hurricane kind of wind attacks them.
It comes at them?
The wind, the skies turned dark. The winds get rough.
The ship's going in every direction
and then the winds, the waves start hitting the ship from every direction.
Are they right by the land Now, are they deep in the ocean now?
Okay, now listen,
let me go back.
Ally is the one who made ease for travel in the land and in the sea for you,
You say you're
for you. You is close
the word you is close the word they is
far until you were boarding on the ships.
The word you means what you are still
close.
Well
be him then does then the winds or the ship's sailed away with not with you. But with
then what just happened
you're getting further away from land.
Then the wind came, they came at the ships and the waves hit them.
The waves didn't hit the ship. The waves hit the people
which means the waves are coming and people are on the ship and they're
getting smacked by a wave and they're just this way and that way.
But are they near or are they far?
They're way out there in the middle of nowhere
and their distances captured in the word they you
see the idea began with the clothes which was you
and it switched over to
they now they're in the middle of the ocean
and
and they realize that they are going to be overcome.
There are going to be overcome by these waves. One more tsunami.
One more giant wave and they're done. It's over
because the last one destroyed so many things.
The next one's gonna finish everything off
then that I will love
now the camera is on the ship and these people are realizing that they're about to die
and they turned to a lot
making their religion sincerely to him for the first time.
there is no distraction between them and their dogs,
they're not thinking about a movie while they're praying.
They're not thinking about a song while they're praying.
They're not thinking about lunch or dinner while they're praying.
They're not distracted by the next guy who's
still waving his finger while they're doing to
the hood.
They're not looking at the guy who keeps scratching his beard
like
none of it
this time. The dog is pure for a lot.
No other distractions
and you would think at a time when the waves and the
ocean and the people screaming so many things to be distracted by.
But for the first time when death became so close,
none of this was enough to distract you
sincere pure. Just for him
when they do this.
What do they say now let brings the camera into the
guy who's making dough on this ship whose about to drown.
His water is up to the neck already.
He was making a lot like this
And he says letting and jade.
If you were to rescue us mean Hadi from this mess,
we will absolutely. We swear to it. We swear to it absolutely ah lot. I I promise.
I promise. I promise. I'll be so grateful.
I'll be from the kind of people that are grateful. You see they don't say
we will not be, they don't say we'll be grateful.
They say will be from the grateful, there's a difference isn't there.
When you say we'll be grateful.
You're talking about yourself when you're saying we'll be from
the grateful means when they used to be on land.
They knew people that were grateful but they never wanted to be like them.
Yeah a lot. I will be more like my brother now.
Yeah. I'll be I'll be more like my mom. Now.
They had examples.
They didn't care about them
until the wave came and they said I wish I was more like my brother right now.
You see that.
But you know what the camera, I just want you to keep the camera.
The camera showed you land then it showed you see then it showed
you a ship then you showed you you boarding on the ship.
The camera was close to you then this camera stayed
on the land and the ship is going away.
Then from far away you can see that waves are coming from
every direction.
Then the camera zoomed in on top of the
ship and he noticed some people are making blah and
it zoomed in so close that you can actually hear
their dot despite all the noise on the ocean.
And they're asking Allah that they will be from among the grateful
these camera transitions in the Koran
are
I mean I'm only able to say camera because
when you appreciate good camera work in a movie,
you're amazed because these movies,
these scenes they take you from one to the next to the
next to the next and you're just amazed at what happens right?
And these transitions.
This is 1400 plus years ago.
This camera work
inside. An idea.
One of my favorite examples of this kind of motion imagery imagery in the Koran
is actually
in sort of
man. That's
what an amazing night
says
woman as
what is a little absurd
one. Eye out
and look at the cameras,
Muslims are surrounded in the battle of the trench. You remember that
The enemies are coming from two sides
north south,
They're coming from two sides unless says they came
at you from above you and from below you,
they came the enemy came from above you and from
below you.
Now the problem with saying that is if you're on the northern border,
you can only see the army coming from there.
If you're on the southern border, you can only see the army coming from there.
You cannot see the both both ends of the army's coming at the same time.
The only view that can give you both approaching at the same time is what kind of view
aerial view of love provides the aerial view first,
the armies are coming from both sides,
but then that camera moves in
and says, it moves in so close, he says, what is a
when I XyZ were petrified,
you wouldn't even blink. You saw the army's coming and you're like,
how close is the camera?
That's pretty close.
That's all the way to the face
and I can tell you're not even blinking.
Then he says, now look at the look at where the camera is gonna go well
and your hearts were jumping up into your throats.
Mm hmm.
The camera went even closer. Huh?
What's going on inside of you?
Then the camera goes deep inside your soul
And you were making all kinds of assumptions about Allah
you were made. You are having all kinds of thoughts about a lot.
A lot. Even recorded the thoughts you were having the sequence of this.
Ia it began with a view of what
two armies aerial view.
It went to the face, it went to the heart,
it went to all kinds of thoughts that were being
had and you know what's beautiful to the eye right before
was watching with full view, what you were doing.
And then the next day I'll let me show you what my fue. Full view looks like
every angle you can imagine
inside and out.
This is
on the transition of the Koran.
Okay. You guys doing okay on the attention span. I think you should be fine.
Yeah,
Okay, okay, Okay.
Not that it would make a difference because I would still keep going and not care
at all.
I will be selective because our time is running out and I have to finish certain work.
So
I'm gonna be selective in what I give you um
okay, let's do this one inshallah,
Allah
is the walleye
of those who believe
those who disbelieve
their wedding
is
whether what these are
to who
let me describe, Willie to you for a second.
Willie is a friend who wants to protect you.
Simple definition, Willie is a friend who wants to protect you.
Well,
he is not a friend who actually protects you
is simply a friend who wants to protect you,
who has the intent of protecting you, has this desire to protect you.
Okay, if he's actually protecting you, he becomes mola
when he's engaged in the act of protecting you, then Moola,
If he's expressed the intent and the power to do so,
and he's got the potential to do it, but not necessarily doing it
because it's a
So you don't actually act it out.
It's really okay. Now,
in this
there are two comparisons.
The comparison is between Allah and the believers versus who
the hood and the
disbelievers.
You see that right now,
I want you to understand that both of these between Allah and us.
There's a relationship and that relationship is that he is our
between
and disbelievers, there's a relationship and that relationship is what
the
truth is there,
What is
a Latina girl photo, That's how it is. Okay now,
I need you to think of it this way
in every relationship or at least in most relationships.
There is primary and secondary.
Like the boss is primary and the employee is
secondary,
the creator is primary, the creation is secondary, the teacher is primary,
the student is secondary, right relationship.
There is primary and secondary
in this Allah is the one of those who believe whose primary and secondary
a large primary and where he is or rather believers are
secondary
in the case of disbelievers and
whose primary, who is secondary
is primary, the disbelievers are
secondary.
Now when Allah says, Allah is the willy of those who believe who was mentioned first,
the primary or the secondary.
Allah mentioned the primary first
allies the wedding
and then the secondary is those who believe they are mentioned
second.
If you look at the alternative
the disbelievers side who's the primary again
to who
but a lot already set an example when you, when you give this relationship,
you mentioned the primary first and you mentioned the secondary Second.
How is it then that when it switched over, Allah did not say like
just keep the same,
mentioned the primary than mentioned the secondary rather Allah said instead.
In other words, those who disbelieve
in this strange case,
Allah switch the order of the sentence and
instead of mentioning the primary in the beginning,
he mentioned the primary at the
and
right.
So this is an example of how life is
actually changing the sequence of the language of the idea
on purpose, even though a simpler version would have been what of the second case.
What's an easier way to say the 2nd case.
The hood,
our rallies
of those who
disbelief, that is not what said,
well I didn't say that he made it unusually long.
Now the benefit of that is remarkable.
Nothing can be compared with Allah.
So the word
doesn't even deserve to be mentioned in the same place
in the sentence where Allah had already been mentioned.
So since the law primary was mentioned in the beginning,
there is no other primary that will be like Allah,
so even another primary will be mentioned at the end
switched over.
This is actually two things, it is on the one hand and a a majesty of a loss of
and on the other hand, a denigration of
you with me so far.
But still,
let's make another point,
how did I define Willie,
I forgot
a friend who wants to
protect you For believers
who is
believers have Allah
as what
Willie
uh Disbelievers
have
to who
as well as yes,
okay,
unless has uh
Believers have a lot of 20 and
as mola,
we say in the
no Lana
at the end of mackerel, we say Anton
arenas.
Lana,
the difference between Willie and mola is simple.
Willy is someone who has the intent to protect you,
mola is someone actually engaged in the act of protecting you.
Someone who's actually doing the act of protecting you is not just your willy.
He is also your
I know that
now we have a worldly
but disbelievers also have a willy
but we don't just have a word And we also have a what
the question then comes
if we have a willy and um Ola,
do the disbelievers also have a willy and a
hold on
says
Mohamed
wow, anil Katharina
llama la la home.
That is because Allah is the mola of those who believe
and the Katherine have no Moola for themselves.
The caffeine can have a walleye
but they are not given a
mola. The believers are given away early and they are given a
nola
So hallelujah
in other words, in the word Willie we know that Allah is willing to protect us
in the word mola. We know that Allah is actually
protecting us.
In the case of the disbelievers, they've got to who,
who expressed willingness to protect them but they
actually in reality have no one protecting them
La la la la home,
incredible stuff.
You know when Willie,
Willie and mullah got translated the same exact way he just missed the whole thing.
Just skip the boat altogether.
You got nothing out of it.
You know.
Okay,
now we can move along.
You guys are still doing okay or I'm going to pretend you are
okay.
Let's talk a little bit about manners in the
all that teaches us manners,
but not manners like
sit when you eat
and speak softly and all of that. You okay abdullah everything okay?
You're good. Okay, Goodbye. Okay.
All right
so check this out.
What is the difference between
when I say I intended? Who's doing the act of intending?
I am when I say it was intended.
Who's doing the act of intending?
Hm
february.
I don't speak Scooby doo.
Right.
Hello.
You're right Scooby. The answer is I don't know
when you say it was intended.
There's no way for you to know who's doing the act of
intending.
When you say
it was written
we don't know the writer.
When you say they were helped we don't know the
helper.
When you say she was killed we don't know that
killer you understand.
Now look at the remarkable language.
Was evil intended
for the people
of the world
or
did their master
intend
good for them?
Wow.
There's an intention of evil and there's an intention of
good
when evil is mentioned. What do you find was evil intended?
Was anybody's intention mentioned?
No
the jinn are speaking here and the jin don't even say by
the way we think maybe a lot intended evil maybe intended good.
They say when they speak of evil they say
was evil intended for the people of the earth.
But when it came to good they say we should attribute good to a lot.
So they say what or did their master intend good for them?
You see that
they didn't stick to the same kind of language? The same kind of language.
Was it would have been
was evil intended
or was
good intended
or did he
intend
evil
or good
if you say was evil intended or was good intended then you gave no credit to anybody
if you say was did he intend good or evil than
you are saying he has the possibility of intending evil.
But they don't want to speak about a lot like that.
They have that much other from the very beginning.
So they actually say was evil intended
for those on the earth.
You know the you know the thing about Jin, have you heard me talk about Jin before?
You know you have a great time margin.
I'm not gonna tell you again story
but I'll tell you a
engine story.
Amazing story.
One of my favorite stories
to tell you for five minutes. You can handle it.
The jin used to travel into the sky,
They used to steal some information from angels once in a while
sometimes
get a little bit piece you know and then
cause fitna in the world with that little bit of
information and every time they tried to steal something they
would get followed by a meteor shower or whatever.
Right?
So they were used to going up into the sky
and they had some
this summer they had some places in the sky
where they could sit and they could listen,
they could listen and you know there were spots, they hung out in
their parking lots in the universe,
you know,
or car parks, sorry, car parks in the universe
where they go and they just hang out and maybe, you know,
smoke a little and just talk
okay, get it smoke. But anyway,
um,
but so the gin,
then, what happened was when the Koran was coming down,
they described this in so little gin
window, Corrine was coming down, the entire sky
was locked down.
They used to have some places where they went and hung out.
There were, hey, what you guys want to go
to the other side of the moon and just chill.
So they're about to go and they go and security,
an entire army of angels is covering the entire sky.
Unauthorized access
turn around or you will be shot down.
So all the chins are stuck not in the sky, but in the world,
they're stuck in the world.
So there was an excess population of genes in the world because the access to
the sky was shut down and they have no idea why was the sky on
what's going on?
Why can't we go on the roads,
everything's locked up.
So they're hanging out on the, on the earth now they've got nowhere else to go.
So a group of them is walking by
and they just heard some Koran being recited by the
salam
and they say, oh wait a second,
that's why the sky is locked down because when
the revelation comes from Allah Allah since Gabriel,
but he is
I mean, Gabriel has a massive following.
So what Allah, doesn't he locks up the entire sky.
Then Gabriel comes down with the Koran and around him as a battalion,
a legion of angels and nobody else has access to the entire sky,
An entire army of angels comes down so that Gabriel can deliver the
and when they heard just a few words of it, they said, I know what that is.
That is why the sky was shut down.
Oh,
that's awesome.
They immediately recognized it.
This is a unique Khurana.
This is a unique crime.
You know, they could tell,
they could just tell
you know, the koresh would make the allegation that maybe he is possessed by
maybe this Koran comes from
and even the Gin
are saying, no, that ain't us because we get killed.
We can't even get close,
you know? So I had a lot.
Now let's go a little further.
Can you tell me the difference? Look, look at the other been language.
Actually, no, the other one. Language thing is easy enough. Let me give you this one.
What's the difference between Allah gave an example
and an example
was given.
Is there a difference?
Yeah,
for a muslim,
when he hears the Lord gave an example, does he pay extra attention?
Sure,
because it's a lot
for a
when he hears a lot given example, does he pay more attention or less attention.
Listen, I've heard enough about this online business. I don't wanna hear anymore.
No, thank you. I'm done
in psychology and communication psychology.
This is called central and peripheral route persuasion.
I'll tell you what that means.
In simple terms, in simple terms,
it means that when you are trying to convince someone,
the real thing that you should be using is your arguments, your proof,
your evidence, your reasoning,
your content. That should be the real reason why someone should be convinced.
But the world doesn't work like that.
People don't just look at, don't just look at what is being said.
They also look at how it's being said.
They also look at who is saying it,
they also look at how it's being presented,
how long it's been presented. And there are lots of things to look at.
Those are all peripheral, secondary things.
But they become important in communication.
I want to give you an example of that.
You have a hot bar
in the United States. We don't have a lot of imams.
A lot of mushrooms don't have imams.
So we have to, we're desperate. So people like me have to get football.
Just somebody, anybody goes and give a football.
So what happens is is one must shade
marshall, lots of elders in the mustard
and as a matter of time and they're waiting for the
to get up on the member. They don't even know who the hell
is this week
and this young man,
he's got one of those pencil beard, you know the pencil beard is
the lives
okay, drawn by a pencil, okay. He's got one of those pencil beers
and you know, he's got a baseball hat on sideways, got a chain,
it's a big baggy T shirt,
he's walking through the crowd, excuse me, excuse me
making his way to the front.
People are confused,
you're thinking
that's the kind of guy that praise in the back is going to go in the front row,
he keeps going and keeps going and keeps going. He makes it all the way to the men but
he climbs up on the member,
two people have a heart attack
mm hmm
he gets up all the way and he gets to the mic
and he sits down,
there's massive confusion.
Even the guy who's about to give the other one is like
should we kill him? Or
there are some people thinking can I get to the other mustard in time,
My salat even going to count,
you know, do I have to sacrifice a goat to make up for this Jawara or
there's massive confusion
but this guy somehow got away with it. He gives
and he gives an amazing couple.
Oof,
it was amazing.
There are people outside who, you know, usually people who come late to the mustard,
they pray by the shoes because they have no space.
So the people who pray by the shoes, they don't see him. They only what,
They only hear him.
The people inside are questioning whether or not they should kill him.
The people outside are like Mashallah
who was the share.
I wonder if I can give him a hug. I wonder if I can
take a picture with him.
I wonder if he can pat my child on the head and
for my child.
You know, like there's
why is that? Why is there two different reactions?
Because we don't judge what is being said? We also judge
who's saying it. It makes a difference,
doesn't it? It's psychologically it's just true. It happens.
We can't help ourselves.
For some people.
They will, they will see someone old about to speak and they'll stop listening
as one of those
before he even says anything, you might say the most wonderful thing.
Just didn't give him a chance
for some people.
They'll, they'll, they'll see someone young get up and speak and say garbage.
These people, why do they get a real item
under the Junior high waisted,
you know,
people judge before the guy even opens his mouth.
That's true.
So now in the,
it's remarkable that in the Koran in Med any Corrine
Allah says durable Allahu
Allah gave an example why?
Because who's listening believers are listening and
when believers are listening in Medina Koran,
they hear the word Allah and they pay less attention or more attention.
They pay more attention. But in the
hodge
towards the end.
Especially the koresh are tired of listening to this message of islam.
They don't want to hear anything.
So they're not told a lie is giving an example because the
moment they heard the word a lot they would stop paying attention.
So they are told. Yeah, johanna's
first time
people an example is about to be given. Just listen.
Just listen to it.
Just listen carefully.
Forget about who's saying it. Just listen to the message itself.
Just listen to the message itself.
That's really remarkable because it's actually a recognition of the fact that in
some cases when you let people know where the source of the messages,
they'll stop listening.
You have to emphasize the message itself over the speaker.
It needs to happen.
This is not to say that the Koran doesn't pay attention to style.
The Koran is actually makes a pretty big deal out of style.
The Koran itself is evidence that style is important.
The
and their beauty and their flow and their
rhythm is also evidence that style is important.
Did you eat itself? Is evidence that style is important,
right?
But there are some cases where people become so stubborn,
they don't want to hear anything and then you have
to use the other kind of persuasion and say listen.
Just listen to the idea itself. Forget about where it's coming from.
Just listen to an example
or an example is about to be struck. Just listen to it carefully.
Okay I'll give you one more before your break.
Mm one more or
Yeah one More. Okay,
past tense versus present tense.
I ate
a burger.
I eat
I know that you know the difference between past tense and present
tense but I want you to think about it even further.
There is an additional difference,
not just that one is in the past and one is in the present.
There's another difference.
The other difference is the one in the past. I ate a burger. How many times?
one time when you say I eat a burger,
is it possible you eat it more than once?
It is isn't it?
So the present tense can indicate something that happens repeatedly
while the past tense
is something that may have happened how many times
once? Okay.
Now bearing that in mind you'll notice a remarkable use of tenses in the Koran.
Very interesting.
The study of tents in the Koran.
There are two dreams mentioned in the Koran from profits.
Can somebody tell me what the two dreams from profits are?
The dreams of
A and B.
Who's in? Who's in? Who's B.
Ibrahim Ali said I'm good. Who else?
Good.
Ibrahim
Salam. And
interestingly enough when Ibrahim Ali sam saw a dream by the way, what was the dream
slaughtering his son?
He says in the ara film. Anomie.
I see in my dreams
I see in the dream. What tense is he using when he speaks
Presidents
Yusuf ali Salam saw a dream by the way, what was the dream?
The stars, the sun, the moon. You recall that?
He says
I saw 11 stars. The sun of the moon.
To dreams are mentioned one prophet says I see a dream the other says I
I saw a dream now the difference. What did I tell you about?
I eat a burger and I ate a burger. Which one is repeating itself?
The present tense Ibrahim ali Salam says, I see in my dream that I am killing you,
I'm slaughtering you because he didn't see the dream once.
He saw it
over and over and over again,
it doesn't the Koran doesn't have to go and waste details.
There's no wasted time in the Koran wasted words in the Koran.
The president tells itself is enough to let you
know that he saw the dream multiple times.
Yusuf
Salam saw the dream how many times
One time
says in the
I saw 11 stars, the sun and the moon.
He saw it once it was enough to bother him and he went and talked to his dad about it.
Do you understand
even a cooler example of past tense and present tense
is murder,
murder.
Whoever killed
by mistake,
whoever kills
on purpose,
whoever killed by mistake,
whoever kills on purpose immediately one after the other, the switch of tents
and by the way, if you use past and present, like whoever ate
lots of fruit might get sick. Whoever eats lots of fruit might get sick or something
terrible example, but whatever.
Okay,
now the thing is when somebody imagine you, you know,
I'll give the same old example if if you go to, if you have an apartment,
you live in an apartment on the 15th floor and you throw a barbecue and
you know everybody is enjoying the food and you take,
hey, so how's it going? How's the new job? Huh?
That was my what
mistake? How many times you gonna make that mistake?
Hopefully
like
in other words, you killed someone but you killed someone by what?
My mistake and that should happen only
once. Which is why when killing by mistake is mentioned.
The past tense is used because it illustrates something that happens
once
in the same discussion.
A lot talks about murder that is perpetrated on purpose, homicide,
right?
Intent for murder.
And so when that is discussed, the lessons,
whoever kills a believer on purpose kills present tense.
Why? Because if you kill on purpose,
there is danger that you will kill on purpose again
and there's also the possibility that you've probably killed before,
which means there's a danger of continuity
that's captured in the present tense.
The Koran will use past tense and present tense to teach phenomenal lessons,
Even lessons about time and how we think about time,
the way we you and I think about time and
the way Allah sees time are two different things.
You know the expression
every person
will be paid.
Every person
was paid.
Every person will be paid. Every person was paid.
Both of these are used for judgment day in the Koran.
Strange
allies describing judgment day, something that will happen in the future.
I would expect every time he talks about it he will say everyone will be
paid.
He also uses what everyone
was paid. How can you talk about the future and use what tense,
past tense you will notice remarkably in the
Koran every time the Iata about human beings.
Allah will say everyone will be paid
every time the Iata about Allah
Allah will say everyone was paid.
Why?
Because Layla's view of time is not like you are in my view of time.
The human view of time is we can either we look at the past behind us,
we look at the present right now and we are waiting for the future in the future.
For Allah who sees all and knows all the past and the present and the future.
His view of them is
all kinds of
are all done deal. He can talk about all of it as though it's in the past
and why specifically talk about it from a lost perspective.
Why talk about the time in the past tense?
Why? Because if there's one thing for certain knowledge
for all the things that are happening right now,
the certain knowledge is always of the past?
Less knowledge is certain.
It's certain. So you can talk about future events in the past tense. He does that.
Okay,
There's a difference. Also I'm wearing the next section now.
These grammatical nuances and in childlike so are powerful
implications of word declination and things like that.
I'll share a couple of examples of this with you.
Uh my hope was that we can at least finish section Section six today.
That's probably not going to happen.
So I'll just at least give you one example of section six tomorrow.
Okay,
check this out. This is gonna be so cool.
Let me just zoom in on what I have written down here.
There are different ways of saying no
in any language, there are different ways of saying no, of course in Arabic too.
So here's what I mean
when I used to be a teacher,
I used to be a nice guy. I remember that. It didn't work out so well
I walk into a class and my students are making a lot of noise
and I say, hey everyone, no talking
no more talking. I don't want to hear one word from you today,
absolute silence. I'm very upset today.
Oh, when you talk like that, you're supposed to think I'm thinking in my head.
Finally, I got there.
Ah
some authorities. Finally, I get some respect around here
but I was destroyed in the first minute of class
as soon as I finished my comment about no talking everybody be quiet.
The kid right in front of me.
Where is his hand.
Can I get some water
apparently to him when I say no talking, it means
for everybody else,
Not for him.
And as a matter of fact, the word no
is used in degrees of intensity.
Like in other words you could sometimes say no, but you don't really mean no.
Like completely no.
Like if you're a Pakistani or something,
you go to someone's house, they say t what do you say?
No,
none.
Which means hurry up stupid,
you know, and he,
that's what that means.
Or Children. You're running around after Children.
You have to catch me. I'm catching her, I'm catching her. I'm gonna get you know,
okay, I won't get you. No, no, get me get me.
Why the no. Then I'm tickling the baby like no, stop it. No, no, no. Then I stop it.
Will you stop?
What? You know?
So sometimes no, doesn't mean no,
sometimes no, it's not. Absolutely no.
Hey, so you know the wife is upset and the husband says, hey, hey, hey, hey,
you want to go get some food?
No,
no, come on. You know, you want to know
you look like you could use some pizza. No.
Oh,
so sometimes no is not total no, you get it.
But sometimes no is
absolutely no,
absolutely no.
You guys know about this when your wife just says
don't talk to me today,
just back off, walk away and just like
I don't know eat some drink some sugar cane or something, live your life.
Okay,
now here's the thing
in the Quran,
the word La means what?
No,
but sometimes if you look at the screen it says LA
your own
the word after La has
at the end right.
And then if you look at the next line, it says same word La, but the word after has
as opposed to ending with what
it's ending with
ah this is a grammatical lesson
but I want to tell you that in english translation of
the Koran actually both of those are translated the same way
unfortunately,
unfortunately, so
is translated there is no fear.
La Arriba is translated. There is no doubt.
There is no fear Lord,
there is no
doubt but there's a difference and the difference is that when you say La,
when you end with one then actually you are saying for the most part no,
but there's some exception possible.
Once again, I'll say that again, if you end with what
then for the most part it's no but some exception is possible
when you end with ah like
then guess what's being said,
there's absolutely no room for exception whatsoever unless explicitly stated,
no way
judgment day.
Allah says for the most part there's no fear on the
believers will believers be still somewhat afraid on judgment day.
Yeah, they are saved from most fear but some fear is still there he says la
he for the most part there are no sales on judgment day.
For the most part, are there some sales on judgment day? Absolutely.
A lot purchased from believers their money and lives in exchange for Jenna
Allah himself said this.
Most people won't be able to make a sale. Some people's sale will be accepted
on judgment day but it says la
on no sales but actually means no sales for the most part.
He says on judgment day there will be no hula la hula.
There will be no friendship on judgment day. That is not exactly accurate.
It actually means for the most part there
will be no friendship on judgment day because on
judgment day will there be people who are under
Allah shade who are befriended by Allah Absolutely.
So for the most part there is no friendship on judgment day then the I. S. S.
There is no intercession on judgment day.
Nobody will come and speak on your behalf on judgment day.
Nobody wants will say to Allah Allah take it easy on the soma. Let them go into agenda.
Wait, wait,
is that true? Nobody,
nobody will speak on our behalf, Nobody will plead our case. Nobody will say
who is it
And the fact that there is room for the profit to make sure
is inside that little
for the most part there's no Shafal,
can you imagine if that splash of arata?
Yes,
that's scary.
Lori buffet. He
tabu
larry, but is it larry bird larry Boone.
Now,
what's the difference ribbon means? What?
Absolutely no room for any doubt whatsoever. That would be a problem.
If you said well, for the most part,
that would be a problem.
There's absolutely no way to force anyone into
this Dean in under any circumstance whatsoever.
Nobody can be forced into the religion.
This is the korans declaration of freedom of religion.
Under no circumstances. Absolutely not.
For the most part, you can't force someone,
but sometimes you can slap someone to make a muslim,
nope
la la Jolla in la la, that should be super obvious to you.
There's absolutely no one worthy of worship, love, obedience devotion
except a lot Under any circumstance.
Similarly,
for hypocrites,
Allah says there's absolutely no portion for them whatsoever in the afterlife.
None whatsoever
in other words.
These I wanted to highlight these because one of my goals in
this seminar is to show you what is missing in translation.
You're reading translation and those two are going
to be translated exactly the same way.
They're going to be translated exactly the same way.
And this is not all that difficult to learn.
Eventually. If you put the time in, it's less than 200 hours.
It really is maybe 120 hours
even you can get pretty proficient.
I want to give you one last example in
as our break approaches. This is actually pretty amazing.
Make
this
a beautiful or a peaceful
city.
Make this city
peaceful.
These are the prayers of Ibrahim
one time he says make this
a beautiful city or a peaceful city rather.
And then some when he says make this city
peaceful,
which sounds almost the same, Doesn't it
sounds almost the same. But you know, language,
it's all about paying attention.
It's all about looking carefully
when he says make this
a peaceful city.
You know what he's saying?
He's saying, he's looking at a desert,
he's looking at this
and he's telling
to take this this nothing, this barren land and turn it into a city.
Not only a city turned this into a
peaceful city.
In other words when he says make this a peaceful city.
This is when he first came to market and there was nothing there.
And he used his imagination and he looked at this nothing and said, yeah,
I think that they can be a city here.
This this this is pretty pretty good. We should have a city here
and turned this into a peaceful city.
Years later he came back
when he came back,
was there a city there already
there was a city there
when the city was already there. He doesn't say make this a peaceful city.
Now it's a city already. So he calls it a city, he says Lord master make this city
peaceful.
Make the city peaceful.
In other words, the language here is telling you the chronology of the prayers.
One prayer is way in the back way early when it wasn't really formulated as a city yet.
And the other one when it was fully formed as a city.
Ibrahim is when it was fully formed as a city.
What do you believe?
Surprise of love?
Ibrahim Ali speaking of Ibrahim Ali Salam.
Since I have a few minutes,
I'll just tell you one or two things about him that are super awesome.
Ibrahim Ali Salam makes these doors
ah in in Alberta
And he asks for two things for the city
dominant dominant
and what?
So he asked for peace and he asked for fruits. You can call fruits prosperity.
You can also look at this as
law and order
on the one hand,
plus
strong economy
on the other hand,
I'm using CNN language now
to have a stable society today. What do you need
any law and order?
And you also need a strong
economy.
If you don't have law and order and you have good
business is the problem is those businesses can get robbed.
People can get stolen from
their money isn't safe. Their house isn't safe. Their business isn't safe
if you have law and order. But you don't have a strong economy, what happens?
There are no jobs?
There's no businesses,
People don't have enough to eat the society falls apart.
Crime increases revolution increases resistance
against the government increases problems
happen to have a society function in a healthy way.
What do you need?
You need peace.
You need law and order. And what else do you need?
You need prosperity. So he said, yeah, a lot.
When it comes to Mecca make this a city that has peace
and also make this a city that has all kinds of fruit.
It is good economically. It's doing well.
The genius of this man.
Inside just a couple of words,
it's just the entire framework for what a society needs
to function in a proper ways of how to love
today in the world.
You have societies that are falling apart either
because there's a problem with law and order
or there's a problem because of
the economy
and sometimes both
and they're both related.
They're both inseparable when you have political corruption.
It usually creates economic problems.
When you have economic corruption, it usually leads to political corruption.
There's two things are hand in hand
and so in the in the
of the profits that you read in the Koran, you'll find tremendous lessons,
tremendous lessons for how society should function even today.
Now, I have six minutes left with you guys.
And in these six minutes let's see if we can knock out at least one example.
Oh, what should I do? What should I do?
Okay, I'll give you one. I'll give you one.
Oh
man,
I think I can do this in six minutes.
You guys have the attention span to last this.
Okay, this is a heavy one. So
listen carefully.
I will,
I will speak quickly now and I will not give you a chance
to answer rhetorical questions because I have six minutes so keep it,
pay attention and stay, hang along, hang on for the ride
70 or more times uses the words
rahim forgiving lovingly,
lovingly and loving and caring.
Forgiving, loving and caring in other words, forgiving comes first,
loving and caring comes second every time except one time in the Koran.
And this is it.
This guy says he knows what goes into the earth and what comes out of it,
he knows what comes down from the sky and what goes up into
the sky and he is loving caring rahim and he is extremely forgiving.
In other words, he reversed the sequence of law for raheem and made it a raheem
which is curious why would he do that? This one place in the current,
let's explore the benefits of this one idea.
The first thing I'd like you to know is that this idea is actually about
the knowledge of Allah because it began with he knows what goes into the earth,
he knows what comes out of the earth, he knows what comes down from the sky,
he knows what goes up into the sky right?
So it's about Allah's knowledge beautifully in the Koran over and over again.
Allah makes an association between knowledge and his love and care.
Knowledge and his love. Knowledge and Rama
and Rama are associated in the Koran. How do we know that Rahman?
What's next?
Alabama?
His Rama has mentioned that his
has mentioned. Him giving elements mentioned immediately
encompassed everything in Rama and
you encompassed everything in loving care and in knowledge.
Loving care and knowledge of
then go a little further.
By the way, somebody remind me tomorrow,
I have to tell you one thing about a democracy.
Just one thing, not the thing I told you last time. Another thing,
a big one,
but tomorrow inshallah I'll forget. So you have to tell me. Okay, anyway,
so Allah says
roger martin. Did you hear mercy? Love Care?
There's association between Rama and between loving care and knowledge.
This idea began with what
knowledge.
So what took precedent?
Loving here Rahim came first.
That's one explanation.
Let's go a little further.
He knows what goes into the earth
like the seed,
right?
What goes into the earth is the seed, He knows what comes out of the earth,
like the what
the plant, the tree, the grass,
okay. He knows what comes down from the sky, what comes down
rain, He knows what goes up into the sky, like the vapor,
the hot air that goes up into the sky. Right?
Okay, let's go to take a step back again. We also go into the earth.
I will go into the earth. You will go into the earth and one day we will also
come out of the earth? Yes,
Allah doesn't just send rain from the sky. He also sends this from the sky.
He also sends revelation from the sky.
He also sends angels of protection from the sky.
He sends all kinds of things from the sky
and he also you know what else rises to the sky. You and I are
rises to the sky
when we pass
will rise to the sky won't it? Our deeds are taken to the sky every day.
The delivery happens every day
of our records,
you know,
So there's a physical up and down and there's a spiritual up and down right
now let's go back again.
So you can see what how this works
when we go into the ground. He knows what goes into the ground.
When we go into the ground, it is the time of our death. Yes.
When we come out of the ground it is the time of our
resurrection, judge the day of resurrection.
When we go into the ground we are looking for Allah's love and care
when we come out of the ground we will be looking for a less forgiveness.
So he mentioned rahim and then he mentioned
muffled
And you know what at the time of and then the next one
what comes down from the sky. What did I say comes down from the sky?
Rain comes what else comes
revelation comes what else comes
huh?
But it comes all of these are acts of a less love and care, aren't they?
So what comes down from the sky is rahman?
It comes what comes from the skies, rahman?
What goes up into the sky? What did I say? It goes up into the sky on a daily basis.
Our deeds, what do our deeds need
forgiveness?
So like I mentioned, what needs love and care?
Then he mentioned what needs forgiveness?
Then he mentions what needs love and care that he mentioned what needs forgiveness
And at the end he mentioned the loving and caring, the forgiving.
There's one last thing
perfection of Koran Justin desire. This is the perfection of the Koran.
What goes into the earth. What did I say?
What did I say? Goes into the earth,
seeds and people.
In other words, what goes into the earth as human and nonhuman?
Isn't that true?
Human and non human?
What what comes from the sky is for humans and also for non humans.
What goes up into the sky is also human and nonhuman. Yes.
So this is not restricted to human activity.
It is about all things.
There are two names of a light at the end, which two names of a light at the end of
and
now I want you to think about this carefully.
Which of these two names are specifically for human beings.
Is Al rahim specifically for human beings or
specifically for human beings
unlawful.
Why is that specific for human beings because trees don't ask for forgiveness.
They haven't done anything wrong. We do things wrong to the trees.
They didn't do anything wrong. Katz said, don't ask us to far.
No
dogs don't ask for us. Their father,
we asked for a step part. Isn't that true?
Because the IA is universal,
The Universal Name of the Law Comes 1st.
If the idea was not universal, if the idea was about us, then what would come first?
The name that is specific to us. It has more to do with us than anybody else.
And that is the name of
it was put in the secondary position because the
idea itself is actually not only about us,
you will now learn that all over the Koran when a lesson
you check it yourself. 70 plus cases every single time. Allah mentions
rahim the Ia is about human beings.
The idea is about human beings.
This idea is the only one that is human beings and beyond.
So he mentioned it to him first.
So the Universal goes with the Universal,
the special goes the specific goals with this specific is the perfection of the
I can't think of any speech of Allah,
any speech of anyone other than Allah can do this.
Who can pull this off.
There are other issues that I wanted to talk to you about that.
We didn't get time to discuss today, but hopefully inshallah,
we'll get a chance to discuss them tomorrow.
I'll give you a quick preview. So I'll let you guys go the tomorrow.
I'll be talking about the stories in the Koran.
Why are the stories in the order that they are will have a long
healthy discussion about why Allah uses the word we in the Koran for himself.
A lot of people are curious about that.
We're going to have a conversation about, for example,
why does the less swear by different kinds of things in the Koran?
We're gonna talk about how people claim that there are mistakes in the Koran,
grammatical mistakes in the Koran.
I'll at least give you one or two examples of that.
We're gonna talk about the order of the Sierras and the Koran
because they're clearly not in chronological order. So what order is it?
What's the shura anyway,
we'll talk about that tomorrow and our concluding session,
which is our most fun session we are actually going to.
Um
I'll keep it a surprise.
I'll give you a surprise. Yes.
Yeah.